Guide to the National Education Association-Committees records, 1857-1996 NEA1003.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Committee on Professional Ethics, 1903-1983; 1960-1975; Series 6; 20.5 Linear Feet
  - Publications-"Provisions in State Professional Practices and Standards Laws Relating to Ethics", October 1973; Series 6 (Box 1225, Folder 26)
  - Publications-Reports of NEA Committees, 1903-1929; Series 6 (Box 1225, Folder 27)
  - Publications-"The Role of the Code in the Education Profession", July 1963; Series 6 (Box 1225, Folder 28)
  - Publications-Selected References-Ethics, August 1958; Series 6 (Box 1225, Folder 29)
  - Publications-Selected References-Ethics, August 1960; Series 6 (Box 1225, Folder 30)
  - Publications-State and Local Projects in Professional Ethics, 1951; Series 6 (Box 1225, Folder 31)
  - Publications-"Two Times Two is Five", circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1225, Folder 32)
  - Publications-"What Does the Code of Ethics Mean to Us?", July 1954; Series 6 (Box 1225, Folder 33)
  - Publicity about Ethics, 1962; Series 6 (Box 1225, Folder 34)
  - Questionnaires, 1968-1970; Series 6 (Box 1225, Folder 35)
  - Referred Cases to Ethics Committee, 1956-1966; Series 6 (Box 1226, Folder 1)
  - Referred Cases to Ethics Committee, 1962-1964; Series 6 (Box 1226, Folder 2)
  - Referred Cases to Ethics Committee, 1967; Series 6 (Box 1226, Folder 3)
  - Replies from State Associations to Letter from RBK and JHM Regarding Implementation, 1963; Series 6 (Box 1226, Folder 4)
  - Report, May 1974; Series 6 (Box 1226, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1929-1950; Series 6 (Box 1521, Folder 3)
  - Saint Johns University Crisis, 1965-1966; Series 6 (Box 1226, Folder 6)
  - Sanctions, 1966-1969; Series 6 (Box 1226, Folder 7)
  - Sanctions-Florida, 1967; Series 6 (Box 1226, Folder 8)
  - Sanctions-Professional, 1962-1968; Series 6 (Box 1226, Folder 9)
  - Strikebreakers, 1972; Series 6 (Box 1226, Folder 10)
  - Strikes, 1970; Series 6 (Box 1227, Folder 1)
  - Teacher Rights, 1973; Series 6 (Box 1227, Folder 2)
  - Teacher Rights Programs, 1975; Series 6 (Box 1227, Folder 3)
  - Teacher Training Project, 1941-1955; Series 6 (Box 1227, Folder 4)
  - Textbook Controversies, 1974-1975; Series 6 (Box 1227, Folder 5)
  - Tours, 1968-1974; Series 6 (Box 1227, Folder 6)
  - Trusteeship, 1968-1970; Series 6 (Box 1227, Folder 7)
  - Virgil Rogers Papers-Attack on Battle Creek, Mich. Public Schools, 1952; Series 6; Rogers, Virgil M. (Box 1228, Folder 1)
  - Virgil Rogers Papers-Contents, 1983; Series 6; Rogers, Virgil M. (Box 1228, Folder 2)
  - Virgil Rogers Papers-Dismissal of William H. Johnson, 1945-1946; Series 6; Rogers, Virgil M. (Box 1228, Folder 3)
  - Virgil Rogers Papers-Little Rock Trial, 1958; Series 6; Rogers, Virgil M. (Box 1228, Folder 4)
  - Waterbury, CT, 1969-1970; Series 6 (Box 1228, Folder 5)
  - Wood, Wilda-"The Eye of the Storm", 1970; Series 6 (Box 1228, Folder 6)
  - Wynn, Lauri, 1973; Series 6 (Box 1228, Folder 7)
- Committee on Tenure and Academic Freedom, 1905-1961; 1936-1961; Series 7; 2 Linear Feet
  The Committee on Tenure and Academic Freedom was appointed in 1919, and was made up of five members, three of whom were classroom teachers. The committee was responsible to make known legislation that may curtail freedom in teaching, investigate cases of teacher discharge in violation of academic freedoms and assist them in finding new employment, and cooperate with other organizations that strive to maintain the principles of academic freedom.
  The Committee was dissolved in June 1961, with its duties and responsibilities being passed to the newly created Commission on Professional Rights and Responsibilities.
  Series contains materials created within the Committee on Tenure and Academic Freedom. The files largely include publications regarding tenure and dismissals, and meeting minutes.
  - Compliation of Teacher Tenure Laws Revised as of July 1946, September 1946; series 7 (Box 4316, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1935-1948; Series 7 (Box 1229, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1948-1958; Series 7 (Box 1229, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1959-1961; Series 7 (Box 1229, Folder 3)
  - Publications-"Analysis of Schoolboard Rules: 40 Cities over 100,000 Population", June 1938; Series 7 (Box 1229, Folder 4)
  - Publications-"An Analysis of State Statutes for Six Professions: Accounting, Architects, Lawyers, Nurses, Physicians, and Teachers", June 1938; Series 7 (Box 1229, Folder 5)
  - Publications-"An Analysis of Teacher Tenure Provisions: State and Local", June 1954; Series 7 (Box 1229, Folder 6)
  - Publications-Annual Report, 1949-1952; Series 7 (Box 1229, Folder 7)
  - Publications of the Committee on Tenure and Academic Freedom, 1911-1949, undated; series 7 (Box 4400, Folder 12)
  - Publications-"Court Decisions on Teacher Tenure", March 1948; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 1)
  - Publications-"Court Decisions under Teacher Tenure Laws, 1932-1946", 1947; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 2)
  - Publications-"Critical Analysis of Teacher Tenure", January 1939; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 3)
  - Publications-"Developing Personnel Policies", 1958; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 4)
  - Publications-"Dismissal of Mitchell Ferguson, a Preliminary Report", 1949; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 5)
  - Publications-"Dismissals in Cherokee County, SC", March 1956; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 6)
  - Publications-"Dismissals in Fort Myers, FL", December 1951; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 7)
  - Publications-"Effect of Tenure upon Professional Growth", June 1940; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 8)
  - Publications-"Essentials of a Proper Schoolboard Hearing", October 1945; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 9)
  - Publications-Fact Sheet, circa 1950; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 10)
  - Publications-"Fair Dismissal Procedures for a School System", circa 1950; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 11)
  - Publications-"The First Five Years of Teaching Experience", May 1939; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 12)
  - Publications-"The Freedom of the Public-School Teacher", 1951; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 13)
  - Publications-"A Handbook on Teacher Tenure", May 1936; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 14)
  - Publications-"Institute for Social Science Research, American Enterprise Association, and Roger Freeman", Circa 1958; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 15)
  - Publications-"The Limits of Academic Freedom", June 1939; Series 7 (Box 1230, Folder 16)
  - Publications-"Mandatory State-Adopted Contract Forms", June 1937; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 1)
  - Publications-"Married Women Gainfully Employed", July 1940; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 2)
  - Publications-"Minimum-Salary Laws for Teachers", January 1937; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 3)
  - Publications-"Opinions on Tenure: Schoolboard Members and Superintendents", May 1939; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 4)
  - Publications-"Practical Personnel Policies...Essential for Good Schools", June 1952; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 5)
  - Publications-Report, July 1923; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 6)
  - Publications-Report, 1936; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 7)
  - Publications-Report, 1937-1939; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 8)
  - Publications-Report, 1940-1941; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 9)
  - Publications-Report, 1942-1943; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 10)
  - Publications-Report, 1944-1946; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 11)
  - Publications-Report, 1947-1948; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 12)
  - Publications-Report, 1950-1951; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 13)
  - Publications-"Report of the Committee on Tenure of the National Education Association on the Dismissal of Superintendent R.L. Hunt of Madison, SD", June 1939; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 14)
  - Publications-Report of an Investigation (Los Angeles Heights, TX), November 1948; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 15)
  - Publications-Report of an Investigation (North Syracuse, NY), July 1948; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 16)
  - Publications-"State Minimum Salary Standards for Teachers", November 1944; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 17)
  - Publications-"The Status of Teacher Tenure", June 1938; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 18)
  - Publications-"Teacher Tenure: Analysis and Appraisal", October 1947; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 19)
  - Publications-"Teacher Tenure: Its Status Critically Appraised", January 1942; Series 7 (Box 1231, Folder 20)
  - Publications-"Teacher Tenure Legislation in 1935 to Date", July 1935; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 1)
  - Publications-"Teacher Tenure Legislation in 1937 to Date", October 1937; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 2)
  - Publications-"Teacher Tenure Manual", May 1950; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 3)
  - Publications-"Teacher Tenure, Protect the Children by Protecting the Teachers", 1938; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 4)
  - Publications-"Teacher's Contracts-Principles and Practices", March 1945; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 5)
  - Publications-"Teacher's Contracts-With Special Reference to Adverse Conditions of Employment", 1936; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 6)
  - Publications-"Teacher's Oaths", October 1936; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 7)
  - Publications-"Teacher's Oaths and Related State Requirements", June 1949; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 8)
  - Publications-"Teacher's Oaths-Statutory Requirements and Oath Forms", January 1945; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 9)
  - Publications-"Tenure Legislation-How to Get it, How to Keep it", May 1944; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 10)
  - Publications-"Tenure Policies and Procedures in Teachers Colleges", June 1943; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 11)
  - Publications-"Tenure of School Administrators", April 1939; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 12)
  - Publications-"Tenure-What and Why", circa 1950; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 13)
  - Publications-"Trends in Teacher Tenure thru Legislation and Court Decision", May 1957; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 14)
  - Publications-"Wartime Aspects of Teacher Leaves of Absence", December 1943; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 15)
  - Publications-"What Policies Should Guide the Handling of COntroversial Issues?", June 1957; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 16)
  - Publications-"To Whom May Aggrieved Teachers Appeal?", February 1941; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 17)
  - Publications-"Wisconsin State College, Superior, WI", May 1958; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 18)
  - Publications-"Your Child Deserves...Facts and Faith", June 1954; Series 7 (Box 1232, Folder 19)
  - Report of the Committee on Tenure and Academic Freedom, 1951; series 7 (Box 4400, Folder 13)
  - Report of the Committee on Salaries, Tenure, and pensions of Public School Teachers in the US, July 1905; series 7 (Box 4317, Folder 1, Box 4316, Folder 17)
  - Report of One Hundred on the Problem of Tenure, 1924-1932; series 7 (Box 4332, Folder 16)
  - Report of the Tenure Divsion of the Committee on Salaries, Tenure, and Pensions, July 1922; series 7 (Box 4317, Folder 12)
  - Teacher Tenure in the United States: Report of the Committee of One Hundred on the Problem of Tenure, circa 1926; series 7 (Box 4332, Folder 16)
- Committee on Women's Concerns, 1938-1985; 1973-1985; Series 8; 1.5 Linear Feet
  The Committee on Women's Concerns was created out of the Women's Caucus and the Women's Leadership Training Program of 1979. The Committee received several charges including: multicultural sex equity, programs of concern to women, continuing the Women's Leadership Training, the national media campaign, and sexual harassment.
  Series contains materials created by the Committee on Women's Concerns. The files include agenda books, historical papers, meeting materials including minutes and correspondence.
  - Agenda Book, November 1980; Series 8 (Box 1233, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, January 1981; Series 8 (Box 1233, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, February 1981; Series 8 (Box 1233, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, March 1981; Series 8 (Box 1233, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, November 1981; Series 8 (Box 1233, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, January 1982; Series 8 (Box 1233, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, March 1982; Series 8 (Box 1233, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, November 1982; Series 8 (Box 1233, Folder 8)
  - Agenda Book, June 1983; Series 8 (Box 1233, Folder 9)
  - Conference on Concerns of Minorities and Women, 1982; Series 8 (Box 1234, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1981; Series 8 (Box 1234, Folder 1)
  - Historical [file 1/3], 1979-1982; Series 8 (Box 1234, Folder 2)
  - Historical [file 2/3], 1979-1982; Series 8 (Box 1234, Folder 3)
  - Historical [file 3/3], 1979-1982; Series 8 (Box 1234, Folder 4)
  - Meeting, April 1983; Series 8 (Box 1234, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, November 1980-June 1983; Series 8 (Box 1234, Folder 7)
  - Pertinent Problems of Equal Opportunity, June 1941; series 8 (Box 4317, Folder 3)
  - Progress and Problems in Equal Pay for Equal Work, June 1939; series 8 (Box 4317, Folder 4)
  - Protecting the Employment Status of Women, June 1939; series 8 (Box 4317, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1981-1985; Series 8 (Box 1235, Folder 1)
  - Status of the Married Woman TeacherJune 1938, series 8 (Box 4317, Folder 8)
  - Variations in Personnel Practices Affecting Teachers, June 1938; series 8 (Box 4317, Folder 7)
  - Women's Issues Conference, 1981; Series 8 (Box 1235, Folder 2)
  - Women's Leadership Development Training Series: Group Process Skills Leading Toward Multicultural Sex Equity Level II, Module 2 Trainer's Manual [File 1/5], 1982; series 8 (Box 4493, Folder 5)
  - Women's Leadership Development Training Series: Group Process Skills Leading Toward Multicultural Sex Equity Level II, Module 2 Trainer's Manual [File 2/5], 1982; series 8 (Box 4493, Folder 6)
  - Women's Leadership Development Training Series: Group Process Skills Leading Toward Multicultural Sex Equity Level II, Module 2 Trainer's Manual [File 3/5], 1982; series 8 (Box 4493, Folder 7)
  - Women's Leadership Development Training Series: Group Process Skills Leading Toward Multicultural Sex Equity Level II, Module 2 Trainer's Manual [File 4/5], 1982; series 8 (Box 4493, Folder 8)
  - Women's Leadership Development Training Series: Group Process Skills Leading Toward Multicultural Sex Equity Level II, Module 2 Trainer's Manual [File 5/5], 1982; series 8 (Box 4493, Folder 9)
- Committee Reports, 1894-1993; Series 9; 3.5 Linear Feet
  Series contains various committee reports of minor committees. The files include final reports from numerous committees, largely created by the National Council of Education.
  - Advisory Committee on Membership Recommendations, 1996 - 2002; Series 9 (Box 4968, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Committee on Membership Recommendations, 1997 - 1998; Series 9 (Box 4968, Folder 5)
  - Advisory Committee on Membership Recommendations, 1999 - 2002; Series 9 (Box 4968, Folder 6)
  - Advisory Committee on Membership Recommendations, 2000 - 2002; Series 9 (Box 4968, Folder 7)
  - Advisory Committee on Membership Recommendations, 2002; Series 9 (Box 4968, Folder 8)
  - Advisory Committee on Membership Recommendations, 2003 - 2004; Series 9 (Box 4968, Folder 9)
  - Bicentennial Subcommittee [NEA Bicentennial Program Booklets], 1975-1976; Series 9 (Box 4061, Folder 3)
  - Bulletin of Information for Nursery Schools, Bulletins 1-5, 1933-1936; Series 9 (Box 4702, Folder 1)
  - Campaign and Election Regulations and Requirements, 1998-2003; Series 9 (Box 4645, Folder 2)
  - Committee of Fifteen on Geometry Syllabus, July 1912; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 1)
  - Committee of One Hundred on Classroom Teacher's Problems, 1925-1926; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 2)
  - Committee of One Hundred on Rural Teacher's Problems, July 1926; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 3)
  - Committee of One Hundred on Tenure Problems, 1924-1932; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 4)
  - Committee of Seventeen on the Professional Preparation of High School Teachers, July 1907; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 5)
  - Committee of Ten on Secondary School Studies, 1894; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 6)
  - Committee of Twelve on Rural Schools, 1897; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Amending the Charter, 1935-1936; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Behavior Problems, 1926-1928; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 9)
  - Committee on Character Education, 1923-1926; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Civil Service for Teachers, 1934; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 11)
  - Committee on College Entrance Requirements, July 1899; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 12)
  - Committee on Community Relations, July 1926; Series 9 (Box 1236, Folder 13)
  - Committee on Cooperatives, 1938-1941; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 1)
  - Committee on the Economic Status of the Rural Teacher, 1937-1939; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 2)
  - Committee on the Economic Status of the Teacher, 1931-1935; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Education of the Handicapped, 1979 - 1980; series 9 (Box 4493, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Equal Opportunity, 1924-1941; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Ethics of the Profession, July 1926; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Financing Delegates, 1922-1923; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Junior High Schools, July 1907; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Normal Schools, July 1899; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Pensions, July 1923; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 9)
  - Committee on the Problem of Retirement Allowances, 1924-1935; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Propaganda in the Schools, July 1929; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Records Consulant Report, undated; series 9 (Box 4400, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Reorganization, 1935-1936; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 12)
  - Committee on the Revision of Departments, 1924-1926; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 13)
  - Committee on Salaries, Tenure, and Pensions, 1918-1922; Series 9 (Box 1237, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Salaries, Tenure, and Pensions of Public School Teachers in the United States, July 1905; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 1)
  - Committee on School House Planning, 1925; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Social-Economic Goals of America, 1933-1937; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Standards, Requirements, and Credits of Teachers in the Service, July 1926; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Taxation as Related to Public Education, July 1905; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Teacher Preparation and Certification, 1942-1945; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Teacher's Salaries and Cost of Living, January 1913; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Thrift Education, 1917-1924; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Visual Education, 1924; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 9)
  - Committee on the Year-Round School, 1969; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Visual Education, 1923-1924; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 11)
  - Committee Upon Vocational Education and Vocational Guidance, 1914; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 12)
  - Consumer Cooperatives: Report of the Committee on Cooperatives, 1939 and 1940, for Presentation to the Representative Assembly at Milwaukee, June 30 - July 4, 1940, circa 1941; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 8)
  - Contributions of Classroom Teachers to the Solution of Special Problems: Report of the Committee of One Hundred on Classroom Teachers problems, circa 1926; series 9 (Box 4332, Folder 17)
  - The Cooperative Movement in Secondary Schools: A Sampling Study in Thirteen States, 1941-42, May 1942; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 9)
  - Cooperatives in the United States; Illustrative and General Overview Reports from 16 states, 1941; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 10)
  - Credentials Committee Meeting [Minutes and Memorandum], October 1979 - November 1979; series 9 (Box 4493, Folder 11)
  - Dynamic Activity Committee, 1934; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 13)
  - The Economic Status of Rural Teachers; A Preliminary Report of a Survey of 11,000 Rural Teachers, June 1938; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 11)
  - Education of Mental Defective, the Blind, the Deaf and the Crippled in the Public Schools, circa 1922; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 12)
  - Erase the Bias: A Pay Equity Guide to Eliminating Race and Sex Bias from Wage Setting Systems, 1993; series 9 (Box 4351, Folder 5)
  - Essentials of a Proper Schoolboard Hearing, October 1945; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 13)
  - A Fair Start in Life for the Country Child; Committee on the Economic Status of the Rural Teacher, circa 1939; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 14)
  - Final Report of the National Committee of Fifteen on Geometry Syllabus, July 1912; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 15)
  - Final Report of the Committee on Uniform Records and Reports to the National Council, February 1912; Series 9 (Box 4139, Folder 6)
  - Guidelines to Fringe Benefits for members of the Teaching Profession (Teacher Benefit Committee), 1969; Series 9 (Box 4056, Folder 10)
  - Human Relations Committee Meeting Minutes, February 27 1980 - February 28 1980; series 9 (Box 4493, Folder 12)
  - Implications of Social-Economic Goals for Education: A Report of the Committee on Social-Economic Goals of America, 1937; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 16)
  - Instruction and Professional Development Committee, 1979 - 1980; series 9 (Box 4493, Folder 13)
  - Joint Committee on Grammatical Nomenclature, 1923; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 14)
  - Joint Committee of the NEA and the American Association of Museums, 1926-1927; Series 9 (Box 1238, Folder 15)
  - Minority Affairs Committee, September 1979 - January 1980; series 9 (Box 4493, Folder 14)
  - The National Committee on Education by Radio: Reprint from "The Educational Record," July, 1931, circa 1931; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 17)
  - NEA Proceedings: Executive Committee's Report and Report of the Joint Committee on Health Problems in Education, 1936-1937; series 9 (Box 4297, Folder 21)
  - A Plan for a Teachers' Home: Home Bulletin No. 1 and 2, circa 1926; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 18)
  - Problems and Principles in Scheduling of teachers Salaries: Report of the Committee on Salaries, 1940; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 19)
  - A Proposal for a Complete Study of the Structure of the NEA, January 1965; Series 9 (Box 4049, Folder 15)
  - Redefining Accountability: Improving Student Learning by Building Capacity, February 2007; Series 9 (Box 4665, Folder 13)
  - Report of the Budget Committee, 1938-1959; Series 9 (Box 4095, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Committee on Civil Service for Teachers of the NEA, July 1934; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 20)
  - Report of the Committee on Community Relations, July 1926; series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 21)
  - Report of the Committee on Cooperatives; New York City 1938, series 9 (Box 4317, Folder 22)
  - Report of the Committee on the Economic status of the Teacher of the NEA: Teacher Demand and Supply in the Public Elementary and Secondary Schools of the US, July 1931; series 9 (Box 4318, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Committee on Fifteen on Elementary Education with the Reports of the Sub-Committees: On the Training of Teachers; On the Correlation of Studies in Elementary Education; On the Organization of City School Systems, 1895; series 9 (Box 4318, Folder 2)
  - Report of the Committee on Homes for Retired Teachers, circa 1926; series 9 (Box 4318, Folder 3)
  - Report of the Committee on Reciprocity, Circa 1948; series 9 (Box 4493, Folder 15)
  - Report of the Committee on School House Planning, 1925; series 9 (Box 4318, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Committee of Seventeen on the Professional Preparation of High School Teachers, July 1907; series 9 (Box 4332, Folder 18)
  - Report of the Committee on the Social-Economic Goals of America: A Descriptive Bibliography of Social-Economic Education, 1935; series 9 (Box 4318, Folder 5)
  - Report of the Committee on Taxation as Related to Public Education, July 1905; series 9 n (Box 4318, Folder 6)
  - Report of the NEA Special Committee on Educational Technology, Undated; Series 9 (Box 5067, Folder 2)
  - Report on the Committee on Teachers' Salaries and Cost of Living, January 1913; series 9 (Box 4318, Folder 7)